Guide to the Saint Andrew's Society collection, 1861-1995
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
Saint Andrew's Society collection
1861-1995
C0085
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
3.5 linear feet, 7 boxes
This collection contains records of the Saint Andrew's Society and books on Scotland and Scottish Clans. Records include newsletters, letters and pamphlets about the ongoings of the Saint Andrew's Society along with ledgers documenting the society's financial transactions during the period of 1861-1956.
Saint Andrew's Society of Washington, D.C.
Box 1
Box 2
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donated by the Saint Andrew's Society of Washington, D.C., in 2003.
Historical Information
The Saint Andrew's Society of Washington, D.C., is a charitable cultural organization for men of Scottish birth or ancestry that works to continue Scottish traditions and culture, promote social activities among its members, and to provide financial assistance to people of Scottish descent.
The Society sponsors a series of annual events that are open to the public, including the Burns Nicht Dinner (January), Winter Ceilidh (February), Kirkin' o' the Tartan at the National Cathedral (April), Tartan Ball (November), and the Alexandria Scottish Christmas Walk (December). Its members also take part in a number of affiliated events, including the National Tartan Day activities, the Virginia Scottish Games, and the Alexandria Scottish Heritage Fair.
The Saint Andrew's Society was officially founded in 1855 and incorporated in 1908. It succeeds the previous Saint Andrew's society in the Alexandria area of Virginia which had its first documented assembly in 1788.
Scope and Content
This collection contains books on Scotland and Scottish clans, and records of the Saint Andrew's Society. Records include newsletters, letters, photographs, pamphlets, schedules, meeting minutes, and ledgers documenting financial transactions between 1861-1956.
Arrangement
Organized by record type and chronologically.
Related Material
Special Collections Research Center also holds the
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
St. Andrew's Society of Washington, D.C.
Document Types:
Account books.; Newsletters.
Geographical Names:
Scotland.; Washington (D.C.)
Contents List
- Newsletter No. 65, January 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Newsletter No. 66, May 1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Newsletter No. 68, January 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Newsletter No. 74, September 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Newsletter No. 75, November 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Newsletter No. 76, January 1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Newsletter No. 77, March 1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Newsletter No. 79, July 1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Newsletter No. 80, September 1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Newsletter No. 81, November 1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Newsletter No. 82, January 1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Newsletter No. 83, March 1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Newsletter No. 84 with Letters, May 1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Newsletter No. 85, July 1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Newsletter No. 86, September 1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Newsletter No. 87, January 1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Newsletter No. 88, March 1968 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Newsletter No. 89, May 1968 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Newsletter No. 90, July 1968 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Newsletter No. 91, September 1968 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Newsletter No. 92, November 1968 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Newsletter No. 93, January 1969 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Newsletter No. 95, May 1969 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Newsletter No. 96, July 1969 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Newsletter No. 97, September 1969 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Newsletter No. 98, November 1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Newsletter No. 99, January 1970 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Newsletter No. 100, March - May 1970 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Newsletter No. 102, January 1971 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Newsletter No. 103, March 1971 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Newsletter No. 104, May 1971 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Newsletter No. 105, July 1971 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Newsletter No. 106, September 1971 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Newsletter No. 107, January 1971 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Newsletter No. 109, March 1972 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Newsletter No. 110, May 1972 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Newsletter No. 111, July 1972 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Newsletter No. 112, September 1972 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Newsletter No. 113, November 1972 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Newsletter No. 114, January 1973 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Newsletter No. 115, March 1973 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Newsletter No. 116, May 1973 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Newsletter No. 117 and Note, July 1973 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Newsletter No. 118, September 1973 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Newsletter No. 119, November 1973 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Newsletter No. 120, January 1974 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Newsletter No. 121, March 1974 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Newsletter No. 122, May 1974 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Newsletter No. 123, July 1974 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Newsletter No. 124, September 1974 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Newsletter No. 125, November 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Newsletter No. 126, January 1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Newsletter No. 127, March 1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Newsletter No. 128, May 1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Newsletter No. 129, July 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Newsletter No. 130, September 1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Newsletter No. 131, November 1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Newsletter No. 132, January 1976 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Newsletter No. 133, March 1976 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Newsletter No. 134, May 1976 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Newsletter No. 135, July 1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Newsletter No. 136, September 1976 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Newsletter No. 137, November 1976 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Newsletter No. 138, January 1977 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Newsletter No. 139, March 1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Newsletter No. 140, May 1977 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Newsletter No. 141, July 1977 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Newsletter No. 142, September 1977 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Newsletter No. 143, November 1977 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Newsletter No. 145, March 1978 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Newsletter No. 146, May 1978 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Newsletter No. 147, July 1978 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Newsletter No. 149, November 1978 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Newsletter No. 150, January 1979 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Newsletter No. 151, March 1979 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Newsletter No. 152, May 1979 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Newsletter No. 153, July 1979 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Newsletter No. 154, September 1979 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Newsletter No. 155, November 1979 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Newsletter No. 156, January 1980 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Newsletter No. 157, March 1980 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Newsletter No. 158, May 1980 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Newsletter No. 159, July 1980 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Newsletter No. 160, September 1980 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Newsletter No. 161, January - February 1981 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Newsletter No. 162, March - April 1981 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Newsletter No. 168, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Newsletter No. 169, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Newsletter No. 173, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Newsletter No. 176, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Newsletter No. 178, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Newsletter No. 180, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Newsletter No. 181, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Newsletter No. 182, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Newsletter No. 184, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Newsletter No. 185, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Newsletter No. 186, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Newsletter No. 187, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Newsletter No. 188, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Newsletter No. 191, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Newsletter No. 192, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Newsletter No. 193, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Newsletter No. 194, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Newsletter No. 196, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Newsletter No. 197, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Newsletter No. 198, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Newsletter No. 199, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Newsletter No. 200, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Newsletters Collection, May 1964 - March 1968 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- T. Henderson Letters and Collection, 1953 - 1973 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Transcription of Robert Burns Address delivered by Dr. David Daiches, January 23, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Carleton F. Smith Photographs of the Tartan Ball, November 4, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- The Glasgow Herald, December 22, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Grand Opening of the Archives and Library at Hearst Hall, October 30, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Tasting of the Single Malt Invitation, September 20, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Members Dinner Meeting, September 10, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Jefferson Cup Ladies Day Ad, September 7, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Joint Meeting of Scottish Societies Ad, June 11, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Norman Lee Barr, III Application for Membership, December 5, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- William Reginald Campbell Application for Membership, December 25, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Yearly Schedule, February 1, 1993 - January 29, 1194 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- New Member List, September 14, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Saint Andrew's Society of Washington, D.C. Acceptance Letters, April 3, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Saint Andrew's Society of Washington, D.C. Members Meeting Request Letters, April 3, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Minutes of Board Meetings, April 2, 1991 - January 5, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Financial Statements, September 30, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Financial Statements, September 30, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Financial Statements, April 30, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Promotional Pamphlets, Correspondences and Photo of Peter Marshall, May 2, 1943 - April 23, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- The Posterity of the Three Brethren, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Short History of the Highland Brigade and Regiments, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Clan Chattan, Vol. VII - No. 1, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Clan Donnachaidh Annual, 1978 - 1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Mackay Regiments, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Life and Works of Robert Burns, Part I, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Life and Works of Robert Burns, Part II, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Life and Works of Robert Burns, Part III, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Life and Works of Robert Burns, Part V, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Life and Works of Robert Burns, Part VI, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Life and Works of Robert Burns, Part VII, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Life and Works of Robert Burns, Part VIII, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Life and Works of Robert Burns, Part IX, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Life and Works of Robert Burns, Part X, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Life and Works of Robert Burns, Part XIV, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Life and Works of Robert Burns, Part XV, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Life and Works of Robert Burns, Part XVI, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Life and Works of Robert Burns, Part XVII, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Life and Works of Robert Burns, Part XVIII, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Life and Works of Robert Burns, Part XIX, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Life and Works of Robert Burns, Part XX, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Life and Works of Robert Burns, Part XXI, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Life and Works of Robert Burns, Part XXII, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Life and Works of Robert Burns, Part XXIII, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Life and Works of Robert Burns, Part XXIV, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Cash Book, 1861 - 1914 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Cash Book, 1919 - 1923 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Cash Book, 1919 - 1923 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Cash Book, April 1926 - November 30, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Cash Book, December 1, 1930 - 1944 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- S.E. Ledger, June 1, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Receipt Book, December 19, 1941 - December 22, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Pins used in book
- Receipt Records, 1954 - 1956 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Articles of Incorporation, 1906 - 1931 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Articles of Incorporation, 1932 - 1951 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Secretary's Members Account Book, 1913 - 1918 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Cash Book, 1954 - 1956 (Box 7, Folder 2)